Finding Aid for the Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo, 2000
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo, 2000
Mus. Arc. 18
Haupt, Irene
1 box (71 photographs)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Contains 71 photographs of musicians who participated in the June in Buffalo Festival 2000 at the University at Buffalo.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Irene Haupt, 2001.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternate Forms
All images are available in the UB Libraries Digital Collections as part of the overall June in Buffalo Collection.
Biographical Note
Irene Haupt, a graduate of the State University of New York at Buffalo, has been documenting the Buffalo arts scene through her photography since 1976. During that time she has worked for, or with, some of the most notable institutions in Buffalo, including the Irish Classical Theatre, Studio Arena Theater, the Kavinoky Theatre, the Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra, the Theatre of Youth, the Albright-Knox Art Gallery, and the State University of New York at Buffalo. In addition to her specialty of theater photography, Irene Haupt has also devoted much of her career to the photography of musicians and musical events. Most notable is her documentation of the contemporary music scene in Buffalo, including coverage of the University at Buffalo's June in Buffalo festival of new music, 1982-1987, and 2000 to the present. Over the course of those years, she has created a visual record that contains images of some of the most significant composers and performers of the last quarter century. The list of names is impressive: Aaron Copland, Morton Feldman, Leo Smit, Virgil Thomson, Steve Reich, Ralph Shapey, Henry Brant, Earle Brown, Ursula Oppens, Jan Williams, Lukas Foss, Philip Glass, Otto Luening, Conlon Nancarrow, Ernst Krenek, Larry Austin, Lejaren Hiller, Elliott Carter, Milton Babbitt, John Cage, Charles Wuorinen, Jacob Druckman, and Yvar Mikhashoff, among others.
The June in Buffalo festival of contemporary music was begun at the University at Buffalo in 1975 by composer Morton Feldman. He directed the festival 1975-1978 and in 1980. The festival was dormant from 1981 through 1985. David Felder revived the festival in 1986 and has been its director since that time.
Scope and Content Note
The collection of Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2000 contains 71 images of participants in the festival for 2000. The list of musicians includes George Crumb, Daniel Druckman, David Felder, Lukas Foss, Philip Glass, Bernard Rands, Steve Reich, Jesse Levine, Roger Reynolds, Augusta Read Thomas, Harvey Sollberger, Jan Williams, and Charles Wuorinen.
Arrangement
One sequence of images in alphabetical order by principal subject of the image.
Container List
- Photographs, June 2000, I.
  - Robert Black, Michael Cameron, and Corrado Canonici, double bassists June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 01)
  - George Crumb, composer with Jan Williams June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 02)
  - George Crumb, composer in rehearsal with Cassatt String Quartet June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 03)
  - George Crumb, composer in rehearsal with Cassatt String Quartet, with technician Ron Parks June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 04)
  - Daniel Druckman, percussionist June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 05)
  - Daniel Druckman, percussionist June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 06)
  - David Felder, composer in front of brick wall June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 07)
  - David Felder, composer June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 08)
  - David Felder, composer smiling June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 09)
  - David Felder, composer smiling June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 10)
  - David Felder, composer in print shirt June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 11)
  - David Felder, composer in print shirt June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 12)
  - David Felder, composer with Magnus Mårtensson and Amy Williams in Baird Hall (building) June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 13)
  - David Felder, composer with Jon Fonville, Roger Reynolds, Augusta Read Thomas, and Bernard Rands June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 14)
  - David Felder, composer watching June in Buffalo Chamber Orchestra rehearsal, with Jean Kopperud, clarinet and James Winn, piano June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 15)
  - David Felder, composer watching June in Buffalo Chamber Orchestra rehearsal June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 16)
  - Lukas Foss, composer/conductor June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 17)
  - Lukas Foss, composer/conductor reading newspaper June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 18)
  - Lukas Foss, composer/conductor, profile June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 19)
  - Lukas Foss, composer/conductor without glasses, angled shot June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 20)
  - Lukas Foss, composer/conductor wearing glasses, angled shot June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 21)
  - Lukas Foss, composer/conductor wearing glasses, angled shot June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 22)
  - Lukas Foss, composer/conductor with Jesse Levine June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 23)
  - Lukas Foss, composer/conductor with Joji Yuasa, seated June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 24)
  - Lukas Foss, composer/conductor with Joji Yuasa June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 25)
  - Lukas Foss, composer/conductor with Bugallo-Williams Piano Duo, facing camera June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 26)
  - Lukas Foss, composer/conductor with Bugallo-Williams Piano Duo, rehearsing June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 27)
  - Lukas Foss, composer/conductor with Bugallo-Williams Piano Duo, rehearsing, side view June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 28)
  - Lukas Foss, composer/conductor with Bugallo-Williams Piano Duo, rehearsing June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 29)
  - Lukas Foss, composer with Jan Williams and Diane Williams June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 30)
  - Lukas Foss, composer/conductor with Jan Williams, Jesse Levine, and David Felder June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 31)
  - Philip Glass, composer holding his glasses June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 32)
  - Philip Glass, composer speaking into microphone June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 33)
  - Philip Glass, composer with David Felder in background June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 34)
  - Philip Glass, composer with David Felder June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 35)
  - Philip Glass, composer with Stephen Rosenthal of the Amherst Saxophone Quartet June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 36)
  - Philip Glass, composer with Amherst Saxophone Quartet, Magnus Mårtensson, and David Felder June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 37)
  - Jesse Levine, violist/conductor playing viola June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 38)
  - Jesse Levine, conductor talking to musicians of the June in Buffalo Chamber Orchestra June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 39)
  - June in Buffalo Photographs June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 40)
  - Jesse Levine, conductor rehearsing the June in Buffalo Chamber Orchestra, with Jayn Rosenfeld, flutist June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 41)
  - Jesse Levine, conductor rehearsing the June in Buffalo Chamber Orchestra, with Jayn Rosenfeld, flutist June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 42)
  - Bernard Rands, composer June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 43)
  - Bernard Rands, composer looking down at score June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 44)
  - Steve Reich, composer June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 45)
  - Steve Reich, composer with Craig Bitterman, percussionist June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 46)
  - Steve Reich, composer with Craig Bitterman, percussionist June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 47)
  - Steve Reich, composer with Craig Bitterman, percussionist and Amy Williams, piano June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 48)
  - Steve Reich, composer with Helena Bugallo, keyboard June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 49)
  - Steve Reich, composer with David Felder June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 50)
  - Steve Reich, composer with David Felder June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 51)
  - Steve Reich, composer with David Felder at Center for the Arts June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 52)
  - Roger Reynolds, composer June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 53)
  - Roger Reynolds and David Felder June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 54)
  - Roger Reynolds and David Felder June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 55)
  - Harvey Sollberger, composer June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 56)
  - Harvey Sollberger, conductor in rehearsal June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 57)
  - Harvey Sollberger, composer lecturing in seminar with students seated around table June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 58)
  - Harvey Sollberger, conductor rehearsing the June in Buffalo Chamber Orchestra June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 59)
  - Harvey Sollberger, conductor rehearsing the June in Buffalo Chamber Orchestra June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 60)
  - June in Buffalo Photographs June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 61)
  - Augusta Read Thomas, composer June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 62)
  - Augusta Read Thomas, composer with members of the Cassatt String Quartet June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 63)
  - Augusta Read Thomas, composer posing with members of the Cassatt String Quartet June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 64)
  - June in Buffalo Photographs June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 65)
  - Jan Williams, conductor rehearsing the June in Buffalo Chamber Orchestra June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 66)
  - Jan Williams, conductor rehearsing the June in Buffalo Chamber Orchestra June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 67)
  - Jan Williams, conductor with Eberhard Blum June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 68)
  - Charles Wuorinen, composer with David Felder and Harvey Sollberger June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 69)
  - Charles Wuorinen, composer with David Felder and Harvey Sollberger June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 70)
  - Mara Gibson on Slee Hall stage, with percussion instruments June 2000, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 71)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
June in Buffalo (Festival) (Buffalo, N.Y.)--Photographs; Composers--Photographs; Music festivals--New York (State)--Buffalo--Photographs; Musicians--Photographs
Genres
Photographs; Portraits
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2001
Mus. Arc. 19
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2001 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2002
Mus. Arc. 20
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2002 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2003
Mus. Arc. 21
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2003 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2004
Mus. Arc. 25
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2004 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2005
Mus. Arc. 27
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2005 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2006
Mus. Arc. 29
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2006 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2007
Mus. Arc. 38
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2007 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2008
Mus. Arc. 39
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2008 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2009
Mus. Arc. 50
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2009 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2010
Mus. Arc. 55
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2010 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2011
Mus. Arc. 56
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2011 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2012
Mus. Arc. 60
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2012 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2013
Mus. Arc. 66
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2013 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2014
Mus. Arc. 67
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2014 June in Buffalo.
June in Buffalo Photograph Collection
A selection of images from the June in Buffalo festivals is available through University at Buffalo Libraries Digital Collections.